Preliminary guide to the Elizabeth "Betita" Sutherland Martínez papers M1854
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Elizabeth "Betita" Sutherland Martínez papers
1940-2009
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Martinez, Elizabeth Sutherland
M1854
90 Linear Feet
198 boxes
Biographical Note
"Betita" Martínez is a Chicana feminist and a long-time community organizer, activist, author, and educator. She has written numerous books and articles on different topics relating to social movements in the Americas. [http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_Martínez 2011]
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, articles, journals, memos, minutes, fliers, notes, pamphlets and other material. Topics include Chicano history, culture, education, Chicano Indian relations, journalism, and movements for social justice. Please note that this collection has not been physically processed, and this document is a preliminary folder listing only.
Access to Collection
Collection is unprocessed but open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 2011. Accession 2011-177.
Women political activists -- United States -- History; Feminism -- United States.; Mexican American women -- History; Martinez, Elizabeth Sutherland; Martinez, Elizabeth Sutherland
- 1. Correspondence
  - Cards from friends & pictures (Box 167, Folder 3)
  - Betita letters, Margaret Halsey, Miscellaneous (Box 167, Folder 2)
  - Poems of Betita, Yves Flavien-letters, notes, 1967-1971 (Box 167, Folder 1)
  - Black/economic powers, Cards, 1970-1971 (Box 166, Folder 4)
  - Cards and invitations (Box 165, Folders 3-4, Box 166, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Texas, Correspondence, Northwest, N.M: palace of governors, Correspondence, New Mexico, Bancroft, Correspondence California, Correspondence: Midwest, Chicago, Kinanza-blacks and immigrants, Editorial + box, Correspondence: misc. University of Michigan, Journal editing Procedures (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Prison letters (part 2), Omaha 11/3/00, 10/18/00 Panel/Oakland (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - Prison letters (part 1) (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Letters, 1996 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Letters from Fremont High School and others, 1997-02-06 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Special Walter Lowentels letters: "You Must Write Book" 1970 + Allen Ginsberg, Odds, ends and puppy dog tails, Family-Mexico, Letters-mother 1976-82 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Themes: Identity, Letters-Jason Harvey, N.Y 1958-59, Cuba 1960's only (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Andre, Howard, Etc., Neal Fange N-toy fair, 1962-1964 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Ernest Chanes, 1965-1966 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Letters, 1994-1995 (Box 63, Folders 4-5)
  - Personal, CLARO + other letters (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - B. Martinez Correspondence. Personal letters (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - B. Martinez Correspondence (series) (Box 54, Folders 1-3, Box 55, Folders 1-4, Box 56, Folders 1-5, Box 57)
  - Letters + Tessa Documents, Notebook (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Lucha (songbook suggestions), Letters to answer (Box 42, Folders 4-5)
  - Correspondence: Professional, General (Box 42, Folders 1-3)
  - Letters, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Letters, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 2, Folders 6-7)
  - Luis Talamantes letter 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 2. Activism: Miscellaneous
  Scope and Contents
  Includes material about war, racism, labor, and the environment, as well as most mixed folders.
  - DVD: Human Rights vs. USA Patriot Act, Miscellaneous photos (Flat-box 178, Folder 1)
  - Photos, Letters, Malcolm X, Correspondence 1994 (Box 166, Folder 2)
  - In color: spectacle of the march (Flat-box 181, Folder 2)
  - Field reports, Political groups (Flat-box 176, Folder 2)
  - Rita and Antonio clips on killing of 1/29/72, 1972 (Flat-box 175, Folder 1)
  - V.B. brigade apps (Flat-box 173, Folder 2)
  - Summer project, Rebel workers, 1964 (Box 166, Folder 3)
  - Essence of 1960's, Autobiographical writings, Betita-publications, Photos (Box 164, Folder 4)
  - Mission + petition, Map of anti-war movement (Box 162, Folder 2)
  - Activists of color (Box 159, Folder 3)
  - East Side Art Alliance, 2007 congreso, War times-11/28/07, Anti-war workshop trainer manual, Latino x guerra meeting (Box 162, Folder 1)
  - Bannerman, Anti-military, Project Yano, Mailing list (Box 161, Folder 3)
  - The I hotel, Mayan voices, The border, Entertainment opening night, Pacific islanders, Program, Publicity, Shades of Power (Box 160, Folder 2)
  - Personal police, Lease-77 federal way, Color of violence (Box 160, Folder 3)
  - U.S economy, Gays + Lesbians, Cultural (Box 158, Folder 2)
  - LATW minutos, Racism images (Box 155, Folder 4)
  - Misc. images, SF Bay Area/race, Protest pics, 2001 census (Box 156, Folder 1)
  - Blacks + war, Masters for Q & A, economics, Events, Latinos x la guerra, Latinos vs. war, Latino forum 5/31 (Box 151, Folder 3)
  - Color anti-war move, ACLU, Middle East anti-war, anti-imperialism info (Box 151, Folder 2)
  - Anti-war-Los Angeles RJ 911, Anti-war, Nebraska (Box 151, Folder 1)
  - Socialist-magazine article, LGBTQ rights, War: repression + hate, NACCS, Police abuse (Box 150, Folder 1)
  - Anti-racism resources + groups, U.S. Social forum, 2007 (Box 149, Folder 3)
  - Globalization, Gentrification, New Orleans (Box 149, Folder 2)
  - Human rights educator, Latino network, Family, Latino community leaders demand action in police in-custody death, Political economy, Immigration test article, "pollutors blitz the EPA on enviromental justice" newsclippings (part 1) (Box 148, Folder 5)
  - Newsclippings (part 2), The left, Maria Brenes (Box 148, Folder 6)
  - Adopt a cross, PCUN update, Gray Panthers, Cultura, A stirring in the land, Guardian, Lobby, ABQ journal, Numero uno (Box 148, Folder 3)
  - Independent progressive politics network, PCUN, Learning from Latin America, Paris hotel, Blunting the wedge, Codex, Towards a strategy of resistance, United Nations and the problem of women and children abuse in 3rd world nations, Mandela speech (Box 148, Folder 2)
  - Solidarity network newclippings (Box 147, Folders 2-4)
  - 10/16/04 peace + justice award, Arc 2000, SNEEN interviews 8/02, 2009, Bio, CV 2002, 2009 (Box 141, Folder 2)
  - Speech ideas, Vanguard, Homeless periacatal solution, Books, Materials, etc. (Box 141, Folder 1)
  - Provisional draft statement of the general line, El suicida de marcial, Chili interview, New Mexico, Marlon Brando, What multi-culturalism is and isn't, writings (misc.) (Box 140, Folder 3)
  - CM #5-design, General, The founding of the workers party Nov. 6. 1979, Basic Marxism, Southern exposure (Box 140, Folder 2)
  - U.S. Commission on civil rights, Violence, The Ku Klux Klan and the struggle for equality, Para gente magazine, Tin tan, The black scholar (Box 140, Folder 1)
  - Guidelines for selecting bias-free textbook and storybooks, Imperialism And world economy, The development of underdevelopement, The American civil war (Box 139, Folder 3)
  - CM #4, Declaration of the rights of working people, Political situation-general current, 1991 (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - U.S repression-general, United Nations, De Anza College (Box 137, Folder 3)
  - Ana Bertha, Staff general, Evaluation, Margo, Paula Silva, CC Meeting (minutes), Coordinating Committee-general (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - Freedom schools, Institute for Multicultural Justice, YWCA, Letters by young activists. CC conflicts '98 (Box 133, Folder 3)
  - CC meeting, Greg. Nov 23 meet, Nov 1 meeting, IRJ-meeting (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - Education, Ethnic studies, Bilingual education, Affirmative action, Media education foundation, Education (Box 133, Folder 2)
  - Video, Durban follow up, Women of Color Resource Center [WCRC], Mexico-6/98, Mediation, NACCS 2003 (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - MALCS [Mujeres Activas en Letras y Cambio Social] 2000, the women foundation 1990's, newsclippings (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - ISR, PA, Cineaste, Breakthrough, Snag magazine, Raza tech, Pocho! Magazine (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - Race, poverty and the environment, El Andar, Latina, Intelligence report, The Nation (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - Teaching tolerance, Ambidextraus, Monthly review, War on Haiti, Justice for Oscar Grant, Top dog, Goldvarg, Keep the peace 2003 (Box 128, Folder 4)
  - Labor fest, Shades of power, Left turn, Baj. Reader, The nation, Intelligence report (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - Line between us, Notes, Social justice, Filero, Race, poverty and the enviroment (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - Canti flas, ISR, Performing arts, Shelter for poverty, Crossing boundaries (Box 127, Folder 4)
  - Year of the eccentric, Viva la causa, La voz de esperanza, Waiting for the rain to fall, Jazz mexico, Left turn, El Tecolote, Project South (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Against the current, Performing art, Network news, 2002 calendar, Voces unidas, La voz de Esperanza, Santa anos lugan barrio (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - A.Wa news, Crisis of the black working class, CAAAV voice, Blu. Ark. Race, poverty and the environment, Intelligence report (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - La voz de Berkeley, Nework news, Coalition, Z magazine, Facing race, Close to slavery, Catalyst project, P.P. enlace comunitario, Jose Torres Tama (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - Race, poverty & the enviroment, Left turn, The popular economist, Chicano magazines, corazon, Newsclippings (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Defining our future (Box 124, Folder 4)
  - Sisters of fire, Old fliers, Homophobia in communities of color, People of color initiatives curriculum, Workshop 2002, POC workshop-plans 2000, workshop/evaluation, POC/Antiracism workshop (Box 123, Folder 3)
  - workshop, Zapatistas, Racial profiling, 2002 (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - Multicultural war, 1990-1992 (Box 121, Folders 2-4)
  - Josefa, The new invaders, Independistas, Conquest, Women warriors, Book one in the beginning, La vida, Million women march '04, art section cover, etc., Lesbianas, Library of Congress, Arizona correspondence (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - WWII, Curanderas, Sports, Josefina Fierro, Luisa Moreno, Cannery workers, Laundry strike, Emma Tenalucaitsolis, Roaring garment, Cotton strike pixley, Depressing + repatriat. (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Isabel Gonzales, Julia Luna Mount, Warriors with words + deeds, Mexicans integrate, Fighting racism, Lulac, GI forum (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - T.A Co-op, T.A. Clinic, The movement begins, La Virgen, Rose T. Jerina/Tierra o Muerte, Texas strike '96-'97, salt of the Earth '94-'93, civil rights congress (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - Bay Area activism-General (Box 116, Folders 1-2)
  - S.E.P. 5/6/00-upset set-up comf. Activism/student 1995-6 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Inner city struggle, Latino students other activism, 1997-8, Oregon student '93 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Outing, YOC, 1994-1998 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Youth study group 1997, Walkout students, Interviews, Youth-mission-organize, Barrios unidos (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Walkout clippings (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Poder, Pomona occupation youth organizing (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Student workers, Campaign development Castlecroft, Are Youth together, S.O.U.L/Oakland S.O.U.L. (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Possible gigs, Attack on Raza, Next trip to N.M Resisting toxic militarism, Viequez verse, The U.S. Navy, Cuba, United Nations, Vieques/okinawa, Gentrification oak (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - The youngest revolution copies, N.M 10/6/07, B.A.SI. Police attacks, Oversea adventure travel asia 2008, the Black scholar, Elisa Facio (+MALCS), Hammer institute, Ideas for speeches, S.F freedom school, Hawaii '09 (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - Points to make in speeches, Justice janitors, To copy for "Z", The black scholar, I.C.E. (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - Marxism, Feminist memoir project '96-'98, Memoir (possible publishers), Trip to Vietnam 03/11 (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Black + Brown, Black Mexico, Black history video in spanish, Tecolote interview 07/2005, "Latina Liberation" reprint, Einstein/socialism, $ expected, Orange CT, socialism (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Statement of unity black/brown, Black Mexico, BBU alliance meeting, Paul Robeson fund, Highlander center, Grant info + release, Rose Tijerina memoirs (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Scenes from Spelman, Chicana por mi raza-interview Aug 23rd, Photo, Forward, Chicana studies I + II, My archive, "black+white" SD articles 1993, Black + Brown alliance (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Mexico City seminar report, Atlanta 3/7/08, Human rights research fund, Correspondence (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Siempre un poquito mas... El arte arma del pueblo, Dixon: guardian articles, Szymanski paper, Militarism as foreign policy, On judging the act of the government of the USSR by Imanuel Wallerstein, US foreign policy alerta (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Short hand notebook world system May '79, Nicaragua 1 & 2, Arte sociadad idealogia (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Raymond Barrio, Editorials on trial correspondence, Reading + notes on reading on ideas, Meeting/minutes position papers, Miscellaneous notes (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Nicaragua, Institute at conference, Sane event 4/29, barard panel, writers congress, ABH (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - DMP constitute, resume, Mid east conference 11/82, Jones former, Guaden, institute associates, islec. Ping ferry, Belafonte, Freedom of information, EA conference, Study-outline history, CIA news articles, Cuba (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - "Still not the last words on Stalin" by Bob Barber, Bob and Teri Sr.- articles and communications, Writing by others (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - San Jose strike, Nicaragua calendar, The league for proletarian socialism in action, Cuba world system socialism… class analysis (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Jerome, Africa and Palestine (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - DWP Miscellaneous paper (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Analysis by other DWP's, Post-dissolution docs (releventro analysis), DWP documents-relevant to analysis, Mortimors meetings, Scrap and ideas, Yenan (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - The Moulding of Communists, Sartre: Between existentialism and Marxism (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Conference activist of color. Grants-Films ARTSF (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - New Raza left-principles. The U.S left CLNCL. New Parties. "the missing piece". Manning Marable. International action center. NCIPA. NCPPC. U.C Berkeley April 26-28, 1991. Conf + I.Ds "plan (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Conamup-Mexico. Against the current. Blood river by Aneb Kgositsie. The road to Gdansk. The soviet union. Memoria. Marxism, lenninism, Ndebele. Mexico journal. Memoria proceso. Challengers interdependence, newsclippings (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Sharon Martinas/Fundi. The Bowen/ Wing family (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Democracia proletaria. Break through 1995. Dialog/ Generations 3/13. Challenging White Supremacy. Feminist, anti-racism, anti-oppression teaching. Anti-Racism educations/organizors network: evaluation and solutions: a summary (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Rainbow Coalition (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Go board meeting RE: proposal for writing current history. Announcing a special seminar. Announcing the creation of a new journal, notes, letters, Etc., 1988-10 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Pulido + Pesquera (Box 98, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, Socialism:Ideal and historic practice, Solidarity founding convention report, Conclusion: authoritarianism, democracy and the transition to socialism, The democratic workers party, Working draft (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Close SOA, Warrior words, Native people, Interventions, Cuba (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Table of contents, Youth page, In public office, Midwest, Introduction, Judge Escodajo, etc. May 1, 2007 police attack, Peacce and Freedom, public office Alanis, Venezuela, Health, New Zapatista, No to war, UN conference on Women, Big anti-migra 3/06 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Temporary help supply service and the temporary labor market, Notes, Interview with Peter Maport head of cacif (rough draft), Newclippings (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - "What color are America's prisons?" Industrial & labor relations review, L.A Contra excerpts, Betita's notes, Revolutionary forces strengthen, Newsclippings (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Kiko Martinez, Fliers, Pamphlets, The real war: low intensity conflicts in Central America, National Rainbow Coalition, Study, UNSS/LPS/IPS (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Kiko Martinez, Fliers, Newsletters, Sociology U859 (7468), The party in a new framework, Tribal peoples survival, Newsclippings (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - History of the democratic workers party (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Week one-Reagan and Austerity, Our Socialism, Notes on class struggle... Winter 1985-86, Political conference (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Social democracy as a historical phenomenon, "the USA in today's world," School, Study group, Democratic workers party, ABC's of socialism teaching manual, Marxism (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Q + A project, Anti-war work, War + Racism, Leaflet, Gulf war bulletin, Q + A background (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - San Mateo College, Migra Protests rejects, Calif-L.A one-stop, Newsclippings, Background treaty (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Plain Speaking [formerly Rebel Worker NJ] (part 2), El Grito del Norte. (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Books: editorials strategy; Acquisitions; contacts (part 2) Plain Speaking [formerly Rebel Worker NJ] (part 1) (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - National network fall-winter 2002, MR article/due 5/1/02, Immigrants and the war 2006 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Oyate/books review 2001, Sweatshop Warriors review, El Tecolote 9/11/02, The fight for everything, Harvest of empire review, MR-summer 2002 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Pegs-10/97, Foreword-Solomon book, Cathleen Rountree women in their 70's, Review Alvarez Books 8/98, Progressive/book review Alvarez/Martinez (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - MS-7/96, Latina 2/3/97, Neo-Liberalism, Teaching Tolerance interview 1997 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - WCRC [Women of Color Resource Center] newsletter women + AA 8/95, Tribuno-9/95, Bear flag, New Presly review 1995, signs articles 1994 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Coyuntora articles Dec. 1992-Grito Del Norte, Tedie Matthews, "Afterword"- 7/94, Race, poverty + environment Fall '93, Nafta Articles- dialogue 1993, LA opinion, 1991, Article on L.A National Catholic Reporter 1992 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - SJ Articles/EPA '92, Textbook article winter 1992-93, Rethinking school article 1992 correspondence, Environmental racism, media extra article, MS 1-8/93-mother, Network news Sept/Oct 1993 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Against current articles March 08, Mexico Stamp, Review of Corn Mothers: forward motion Dec. 1992, Martinez on Mexico 1988 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - SF Review of books, Summer 1989, El Tecolote. Letters protesting racism 1990-1994 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Next book-South End, May 1 events, March 8, International Woman's Day Origins, Reprints, Turkey Day. "Immigrants all" 1989-90 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Baby book, Tupac Amaru y Los Rebeldes de Peru, Othello Act V, Letters, Newsclippings, Etc. (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Henry Kissinger Panama stalemate, John D. Blacken (Flat-box 177, Folder 2)
  - Thomas: My Politics. Out of the war shadows 1968 Peace calendar (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Clippings + brochure, Black Struggle, international, 1971 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Interacial books for children bulletin vol 5-8 (part 2), Ohio Chicanos blast police killing guardian, 1975 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Turning Point, SNCC 1967 calendar, Village Voice '64 + '69, National Catholic Reporter 7/70, Venceremos Brigade, Tricontinental 1972 "Las Chicanas," Interacial books for children-bulletin- vol 5-8 1975 (part 1) (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - My job at SNCC (part 2) (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Unipaz the Women of La Raza, Ideal & New York review, 2 articles- Castro-Cuba, Mississippi, Reviews on Betita '64, '69 + books, My job at SNCC (part 1) (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - The Columbia Rebellion New Politics, The women of La Raza, El problema demografico no se remediara con discriminacion natal, sino con justicia social, La Chicana: a socialist view, Mary Poppins (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Nic Woren newsletter, The People United, Denuncia, El insurgente socialista, Feb. 7, 1975 invitation, Oct 10, 1964 turning point, Marxist studies and third world people: a gap that must close, The Nation Nov. 4, 1961 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - An open letter to activists, The Nation 1961: CIA, NIC bulletin, Free at last, Native Americans (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Laos, The National September 28, 1970, Guardian February 13, 1971, Newclippings, Cuba Notebook (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Minorities/Black struggle- Black Panther Party. Minorities/Black-General. Minorities/Asian (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Urban Research group, To the Colectivo de Octubre. Newsclippings (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Feminism and culture, The consciousness industry, List of materials, Short notes at city council meeting, De Septiembre July 9, 1971. Tawagi Wakawa Shoush, Trip to China '72 (part 1) (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Trip to China '72 (part 2) (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Letters, problems of Communism July/August, 1970 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Communism letters, essays, etc. (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Communist Labor Party, Notebook (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Notebook Bakke II (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Youth Activism, Labor: Miscellaneous (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - "Wartimes" Magazine, Chevy Chase House Letters (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - ER/Internal, Guardian letters, Crime, Justice Committee. Raps on PWP (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Nashville/Debate, Feb 4 Propose, Publicity Julian Bond/TV programs, Alliance for Justice D.C. (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - ISLEC [Institute for Society, Landscape, and Ecosystem Change] evalution 4/86, Documents 4/3/87, ISLEC 2/85-4/86 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - MD on History, Present situation, Militants, Communism, etc. (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - 2nd draft sec. Marxism, Quality of life, M-L model, other documents, Crits/analysis (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - History Sec. SEC. Socialist Movement in the Circia discussion documents (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - DWP Dissolution (Box 49, Folders 4-6)
  - G.O-General 1988-90, Relations, Seminars Publicity. Campaign (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - G.O Brochure, Literature-G.O. (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Dixon CV, Conference on Immigration, Soc. Scholars conference, McCarthyism Symposium (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - R.P Martinez, DWP Analysis (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Theory (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Socialism crisis, Left (general) (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Demo-photos (prints), Unsorted (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - U.C.L.A. hunger strike notes (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - 11/21-22/91 notes, Gadfly newsclips, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Nenna, Lourdes Portillo, Patricia recaludo, Race relations as teens (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - EPA, Big lo letters (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Environment General (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Public opinion, Initiatives-Wash., Opposition to right to die, Euthanism, Church, Suicide, Morality, ethics, Hospitals+ MD's, Fact check (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Articles and correspondence, mother, CPR, Quinlan case, Cruzan case, Busalacchi case, Beva Sanchez Padilla, Mavleon (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Living wills, Bouvia case, Initiatives/ Calif. 1990-Conf, Perestroika + left (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Clarance Thomas hearings/ Anita Hill (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Civil rights, Los Angeles 1992 uprising (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - New California Alliance, Eastern Europe, 1988 elections (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Nica Solidarity work, Nica printers project, Japan, China (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Saul's Cuba film, Ecology-globe-Gaia, USDCA, Left: Peace and Freedom Party (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - C.P.U.S.A M-L [Communist Party of the United States, Marxist-Leninist] documents: U.S (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Indians (Box 32, Folders 4-5)
  - Responses to sexism, Treaty council news, Civil rights digest (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Social Democrats (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - M-L [Marxist-Leninist] study material, L.A Chile, Left-U.S.-General (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - National questions (Box 31, Folder 4)